[dramatic music]
[wood splintering]
[rocks clatter]
[branch snaps]
[thud]
[Ras sighs]
[emotive music]
[buzzing sound]
My master,
it begins.
Get down to the Shadow Dojo.
Set the Gong
of Shattering in place.
[ominous music]
You! Have the last of the
Theroxian texts been translated?
Yes.
Good. Destroy this place
and everything in it.
What about them?
I said everything.
[all gasp]
We no longer need
the Writers of Destiny.
We are the masters
of our destiny now.
[Cinder chuckles]
[Writers of Destiny whimper]
[ominous music crescendos]
♪ Lost in the unknown ♪
♪ So much to see ♪
♪ Together we will rise ♪
♪ We fight ♪
♪ Be a Ninja for what's right ♪
[logo explodes]
[metal clanging]
[tense music]
You two still with me?
[Sora grunts and yelps]
A smoother ride couldn't hurt!
[metal clanking]
[groans] I am not afraid
of anyone or anything,
especially heights!
I'm just closing
my eyes to rest them.
[metal clangs]
-[rock crumbles]
-[Wyldfyre screams]
[Kai grunts]
[Wyldfyre yelling]
[Wyldfyre grunts]
[Wyldfyre pants heavily]
-[Kai] Whoops!
-Whoops?
You're not allowed
to say whoops!
I totally got this!
-[tense music]
-[claw recoils]
Not cool, not cool, not cool!
[Wyldfyre grunts, pants]
-You good, Wyldfyre?
-Yeah.
No thanks to
Mr. "I totally got this."
[metal clangs]
[claw arm whizzing]
[metal thuds]
I totally do got this!
-[rocks crumbling]
-Uh-oh.
-[fireball launches]
-[rock explodes]
Huh?
[sighs] Thanks.
[metal clanging]
[grunting with joy]
I love you.
I love you, ground!
Come on, it wasn't that bad!
No, it was.
But at least we're
out of danger now.
[branch snaps]
[whirring]
[metal clangs]
Forget I said that.
[Nya panting heavily]
We got so turned
around in that storm,
I have no idea
how far out we are.
I know, but we
gotta get to the ritual
of the Blood Moon before--
[groans]
Not now!
No!
More visions?
[groans]
I can't let them come.
Have to force them to go away.
[Lloyd groans]
[dramatic music]
[thunderclap]
[ominous music]
[weapon thuds]
[portal whirring]
[groaning]
[Nya] Lloyd. Lloyd!
-[spell whizzes]
-[Jordana grunts]
Settle down, spell.
I don't know what you
think you've been doing,
playing person
with your fake family,
but I know your true purpose.
You're a spell that
can bridge our world
with Nether-Space.
Please, no. I don't wanna be
just a spell again.
[scoffs] Like you have a choice.
You should thank us.
We're helping you to do
what you were created to do.
[door closes, computer dings]
[engine revs, tires squeal]
[eerie music]
[Sorceress]
Ooh, careful, Zane.
Don't wanna fall and
get a bump on your noggin.
-[electricity sizzles]
-[Zane gasps]
I should be able to overload
this Imperium electro-wall now!
[electricity sizzles]
[thuds]
[triumphant music]
[suspenseful music]
[groans]
[yells]
We've gotta get out!
We gotta get Bonzle
back from that creep.
[fist thuds]
[emotional music]
[surroundings rumbling]
I understand
your emotions, Cole,
but we must remain calm
to find a solution.
He's right!
Any spell storehouse
worth its magic
has a few other trap doors
and secret passages.
Great! Let's find them!
Eh, no.
[grunts] Ah!
-[orb magic buzzes]
-Eureka!
[magic buzzing]
[playful music]
-[creature growls]
-Ah!
-[metal door clangs]
Okay. Someone turned that escape
hatch into a raging Fang Mouth.
Janet.
No big deal.
We'll find another way.
[playful music]
[orb magic buzzes]
See? A secret passage.
Come on!
[grunts]
What?
Hmph. The darkness has
been made solid here.
Fine! We'll have to go
through the deadly
and smelly hidden passageway.
It's just behind this door.
It smells like rotten manure
covered in moldy toe jam.
[sniffs]
I-I don't smell anything.
-[door creaks open]
-No!
Don't tell me it's been hit
with an "infinity door" curse.
[door creaks open]
[door creaks]
[funky upbeat music]
[toaster dings]
Uh... groovy!
[funky upbeat music]
[doors clang shut]
Sorceress, there's tons
of magic stored in here.
Couldn't something
"abracadabra" us out?
Oh, yes.
Good idea.
Now, if only I could remember
what all this stuff is.
[insects chirping]
Looks like a road.
Any idea which way
we should go, Riyu?
[Riyu growls]
Hmm.
No footprints in this direction.
In the Crossroads, they had
street signs everywhere.
Wish someone made
a sign here that says,
"Evil Blood Moon
Ritual Up Ahead."
Anything to show us how
to get there and stop Ras.
[engine roaring]
[dramatic music]
[engine roars]
Was that the girl from Imperium?
The one who hates Sora?
She's got someone captured!
[Riyu barks and growls]
You're right, she's gotta be
going to the Blood Moon ritual!
But we'll never--
Oop, whoa!
Riyu, you're
a fast little dragon,
but there's no way you can
catch up to a moving vehicle--
[Arin yells]
[Riyu shrieks]
Wow, buddy!
You're really flying!
This is actually happening!
Yes!
Let's go!
[Riyu roars]
[engine roars]
Okay. I sense the tension here,
but we don't have to fight
if we just take the
temperature down a notch.
Taking the temperature
down is never my thing!
[fireball blazing]
[fireball explodes]
[swords swish]
[swords clang]
[metal claws thud]
[metal clanking]
[Kai grunts]
[Kai] Like an itch
I can't scratch!
-[fireballs blazing]
-[sword clanging]
[fireball blazes]
Wow! Rontu's training
really worked!
She'd be so proud
of me right now--
-[Sora screams]
-[Sora thuds]
[intense music]
[fireball blazing]
[fireball explodes]
[fireball blazes and explodes]
Come on, Wolf wannabes!
I just hung off
the edge of a cliff.
You don't scare me at all!
The cliff didn't scare me
either, by the way.
[metal clanging]
Hey, Kai!
I got your back!
[fireball blazes]
-[metal clangs]
-[electricity sizzles]
[fireball blazes]
-[fireball explodes]
-Ha, "You got my back."
[laughs] Nice pun!
What's a pun?
Dang, you've got
moves now, Sora!
Someday you might
be as good as me.
[pants] I'm getting there.
I need more practice.
Please don't tell
Lloyd I said that.
[Kai] Okay.
Now we're out of danger.
[engine roars]
[dramatic music]
Whoever she's got in there,
we have to free them.
[engine roars]
Huh?
I thought it was you!
Sorry I can't
remember your name!
Ugh, I hate you Ninjas so much!
[tires squeal]
[Arin grunts]
Get off!
I'd rather get in.
[Arin screams]
[tires squeal]
-Whoa!
-[Jordana gasps]
[Arin and Jordana grunt]
What do you think you're doing?
Let go of that!
[Arin grunts]
[dramatic music]
[Jordana yells and grunts]
[engine roars]
Ugh! Why can't they
ever remember my name?
[engine roars]
Don't worry!
I'm with the Ninja.
Yeah, your outfit
kinda gave that away.
Why are you in that box?
I just like it!
Very comfortable.
Really?
It doesn't look it.
[Bonzle] What's your
elemental power?
Imperiousness to sarcasm?
-[Arin gasps]
-[dramatic music]
-[buttons beeping]
-[gear shift cranks]
-[accelerator blasts]
-Hang on tight!
[engine roars]
-[Arin moans]
-[Bonzle screams]
-[Riyu squawks]
-[buttons beep]
[metal clangs]
-[tires squeal]
-[engine roars]
[Arin moans]
[brakes squeal]
[Bonzle pants]
First time driving?
Believe it or not, no.
Come on, lemme get you
out of that box.
You can't.
It's magically sealed.
-Maybe my spinjitzu--
-[Bonzle] No time!
Ras needs me for his
Blood Moon ritual.
No me, no ritual.
So we gotta get as far away from
Ras and his people as we can.
On it.
[tires squeal]
[dramatic music]
-[tires squeal]
-[Bonzle grunts]
[Bonzle] You swear
you've driven before?
I used to be a top racer!
But not in cars.
In mechs.
And I mostly sat backwards
while my friend drove.
Oh, well that
explains everything.
[grunts and sighs]
[Arin] But don't worry.
We'll be fine.
[engine roars]
[contemplative music]
[Wyldfyre] What now?
I want to blast something again.
[footsteps marching in unison]
[ominous music]
More of those clowns heading
toward the Blood Moon.
That's gotta be where
the ritual's happening.
[eerie music]
Huh.
That gives me an idea.
Nice. I think
we can pull this off.
What?
Maybe one of them uses a crutch.
[Sora sighs]
Okay, whatever.
I'm sure my leg's gonna
hurt like it always did,
and I shouldn't have had
to rest while you all trained.
Huh? It-it
doesn't hurt anymore!
[Wyldfyre grunts and gasps]
What? Are you kidding me?
Rontu was right!
Resting my leg
actually healed it!
Huh! Who knew?
Rontu? I was the first one to
tell you that you should rest.
Yeah, but when a dragon said it,
it turned out to be true.
[Wyldfyre grunts gleefully]
[contemplative music]
[items rustling, box thuds]
[playful music]
An alphabetization spell
probably wouldn't do here.
And morphing into a parrot...
takers?
[quirky music]
Eh, okay.
[items rustling and clanking]
Ah, invisible shoes!
-No.
-[shoe thuds]
Hmm, Anti-Gravity!
Oh no.
-[bottle explodes]
-[Cole exclaims]
[playful music]
Anti-Anti Gravity potion?
Pass.
[bottle explodes]
-[Zane yells]
-[Cole screams]
[metal items clanging]
-Ew.
-[Cole grunts]
-[blob squelches]
-[Cole groans]
[playful music]
[Cole] Can anyone hear me?
What happened to my voice?
[blob squelches]
Get this slimy
blob off my mouth!
Hey, it worked!
My voice is back!
[metal and glass clinking]
[Sorceress groans]
-[Sorceress sniffs, coughs]
-[soft ringing sound]
Definitely not that one.
[Zane coughs]
[Zane groans]
[Cole gasps]
This is not a desirable outcome.
[Sorceress] Don't worry,
you'll be fine.
-[magic buzzing]
-Huh?
I find this destabilizing.
-[stammering]
-It'll wear off soon... I think.
[potion sloshes]
-But--
-Here, smell this.
Does it smell like
newt tail juice?
What does newt tail
juice smell like?
[sniffs]
Ugh, gross!
-[sneezes]
-[soft ringing sound]
[bottle clanks]
-[whines]
-Eh, should have labeled that.
-[bottles clinking]
-[Cole groans]
Why do you have this?
How is this helpful?
But at least you are adorable.
I'm always adorable.
[Cole sneezes]
[soft ringing sound]
Aha! Found it.
My "Instant Opener" spell!
I use it on stubborn
jars of slugs
with lids that won't budge
even after running
them under hot water.
[Sorceress yells]
[bottle smashes]
Hey! I'm sleeping in here.
The good news is you have
lots more of that stuff?
I will admit that
I am out of ideas,
and yet urgency is pressing.
That's it!
[Zane] I cannot see.
Where are we going?
[Cole] The perfect size!
Go through the keyhole
and let us out!
Ah! Now I see your logic.
I'm through!
But the vertical distance
between the keyhole
and the ground
is impossible for me to--
[Zane yells]
-[door creaks open]
-[Cole] Yes!
[triumphant music]
I appear to still
have a problem.
Really?
Should have worn off by now.
Well, I guess you'll just have
to buy larger-sized clothes.
[ominous music]
[Sora] It worked.
We're in!
But there's a lot more
of them than I expected.
[Wyldfyre] And they have
their fancy clanging thing.
[Kai] The Gong of Shattering.
Looks like saving the world's
gonna be even harder
than we thought.
[ominous music crescendos]
[grunts] Look!
[Zane's footsteps rumbling]
[grunts] Flee my impact zone!
[groans]
Told you it would wear off!
[ground rumbles]
[chain clanking]
The Cloud Kingdom!
It appears to be
losing altitude.
That's probably where
they took Bonzle. Let's go!
[dramatic music]
[trilling sounds]
Oh, now how am I
supposed to follow them?
I can't--
Hold it.
-[bottle breaks]
-[soft ringing sound]
It's been a while, Hatty.
Let's see if you can
still do your old tricks.
-[magic whizzing]
-[Sorceress exclaims]
See you at the top!
Whee!
[triumphant music]
[magic whizzing]
[footsteps walking]
[suspenseful music crescendos]
[ominous music]
Position the captives.
Move it!
[chuckles] I'm so gonna enjoy
watching you all be sacrificed
to release the Forbidden Five.
[Sora] Sacrifices?
[Kai] Don't love
the sound of that.
They need them to release
the Forbidden Five,
or else the ritual fails?
[Wyldfyre] Sounds
like you just said,
"Let's blast their chains
and free them."
Wyldfyre, you're always
pickin' up what I'm layin' down.
[footsteps shuffle]
Initiate.
[drumbeat]
[Nokt] Finally,
after long centuries,
we are being called home.
[ominous music crescendos]
Where is Jordana?
She should be here by now.
You ask me, she's super
unreliable, Lord Ras.
You should have sent me after
that spell instead of her.
[Ras growls]
[Sora] Nothing to be afraid of.
We got this.
[Wyldfyre] Who's afraid?
I'm not afraid.
[Sora] I was talking to myself.
Hey!
Lord Ras!
You come here empty-handed?
Where is the spell?
It was stolen by one
of those pesky Ninjas.
You fool!
[thud]
[Ras grunts]
[clicks tongue] Not the
teacher's pet anymore, I guess.
[angry groan]
[Sora] What do you
think all that was?
[Kai] A good distraction.
Let's go!
[dramatic music]
[engine roaring]
[Ras grunts and growls]
[engine roars]
[Ras grunts]
-[Arin grunts]
-[tires squeal]
[Riyu growls]
[roars]
[Riyu roars]
-[Riyu groans]
-[Arin grunts]
Ninja, go!
[magical whirr]
[Arin grunts]
[dramatic music]
[Arin groans in pain]
[Arin grunts]
[Arin groans]
[Arin groans and pants]
[Arin] Ninja never quit--
[yells]
You could be something special.
Too bad the Ninja hold you back.
[groans in pain]
No, they don't!
They're making me better!
[Ras scoffs]
Then how come you
aren't any better?
I stopped you as easily now
as the first time we met.
I was weak like you, once.
[buzzing sound]
[Ras] My Master found me
and taught me the most
important thing in this world.
Strength.
[dramatic music]
[Ras grunts]
[Arin crashes and screams]
[rocks rumbling]
[Arin gasps and sighs]
[Ras growls]
Maybe one day you'll
find a true Master
who can teach you the same.
[tense music]
-[tires squeal]
-[Bonzle] Let me go, weirdo!
[engine roars]
[Arin groans in pain]
-[gentle music]
-[footsteps approaching]
Mom? Dad?
[ominous music]
[Bonzle grunts and pants]
[Bonzle] Let me out!
Let me out of here!
[dramatic music]
The pieces are all
in place, Master!
Your patience and planning
are finally paying off!
And the true power
of all the realms
will be ours.
[closing theme music playing]